https://southbourneschool.co.uk/privacy-policy/

HomeAboutSchool FacilitiesOur TeamJoin Our TeamTestimonials & AccreditationsSchool PoliciesFAQsLanguage CoursesGuide To LevelsAdult Language CoursesGeneral & IntensiveGeneral / Intensive Course PLUSSummer Vacation CoursesExamination CoursesBildungsurlaubJunior Language CoursesSpring CourseSummer CoursesResidential CoursesYear Round Group CoursesHow To Book Your CourseBlogBlogGalleryStudying in BournemouthCOVID – Keeping Safe at SchoolTravelling to BritainSchool ActivitiesOur LocationAccommodation & WelfareHomestayGuesthouses & HotelsAgentsHosting StudentsContact Us
AgentsHostingContact Us
Search for:
Book NowHomeAboutSchool FacilitiesGalleryOur TeamJoin Our TeamTestimonials & AccreditationsSchool PoliciesFAQsLanguage Courses
Starting at Southbourne School of EnglishGuide to Levels
Adult CoursesGeneral & IntensiveGeneral & Intensive PLUSSummer Vacation CoursesExamination CoursesBildungsurlaub
Junior CoursesSummer CoursesResidential CoursesSpring CourseYear-Round Group Courses
How to Book Your CourseInformation on how to apply for your next course and how to pay for it.BlogStudying in BournemouthCOVID – Keeping Safe at SchoolTravelling to BritainSchool ActivitiesOur LocationAccommodation & WelfareHomestayGuesthouses & Hotels
Privacy PolicyThis is the general privacy policy for Southbourne School of EnglishWho we are and what we doWe are a privately owned family-run English Language School that provides teaching for international students.We are a British Council accredited provider of English language and activity.We are a member of English UK, Young Learners English UK, English UK South, Quality English and RALSA.We have three main aims for all our students:Study – we help student to achieve their language goalsSocialise – to make friends from different countriesEnjoy – we support students to make the most of life in the UK; in homestay;in residential boarding school;  experiencing British culture first-hand and visiting tourist destinationsIn order to achieve this we provide a secure and friendly environment where students can feel at home.  We believe this provides the best experience for language learning and development. Our Privacy StatementThe protection of your privacy and personal information is important to us. We make sure that we have appropriate security measures in place and that any other organisation we work with to provide a service also meets the same standard as us.We will respect your privacy. You should receive promotional/marketing emails from us only, and we will make sure that the boxes you need to tick if you are happy to receive marketing are presented clearly and at an appropriate time.We will make it clear at the point when we request your information about what we are collecting it for and how we are going to use it.We will collect and use your personal information if we have your permission or we have sensible business reasons for doing so, e.g. collecting enough information to manage or process your course enrolment.We will minimise the amount of information we collect from you to what we need to deliver the services you need.We will be clear to you what information about you we will collect and how we will use it.We will use personal information only for the purposes for which it was originally collected and we will make sure we delete it securely.Our website and active social media accounts are accessible via the internet. Please remember that if you post any comments or links on any of our sites, they can be read and accessed by anyone.If we, our service providers, or our business partners transfer any information out of the European Economic Area (EEA), it will only be done with the relevant legal instruments and security measures being in place and stated on their individual Privacy Policies. What information we collectWe collect the following information from Students and Group Leaders– Biographical information for our students and group leaders for enrolment purposes: name, date of birth, gender, nationality.– Passport number and expiry date for visa application purposes and UKBA requirements– Information about allergies, medical conditions, medical treatments and room-sharing preferences, for accommodation purposes.– Contact details including postal addresses, e-mail addresses, telephone numbers and parent or guardian’s contact details for consent and safeguarding purposes. We collect the following information from Homestay hosts – Name, date of birth, home address and landline number, mobile phone number, e-mail address, bank details, DBS certificate’s issue date and number, personal character references, signed homestay agreements, signed risk assessments and household description. We collect the following information from Suppliers – Email addresses, telephone numbers, bank account details, processed invoices in the interest of paying suppliers and/or fulfilling a contract.We collect the following information from Employees – Employee’s name, date of birth, home address, mobile number, e-mail address, CV, education history, tax and income details, national insurance number, bank details, DBS certificate’s issue date and number, referees’ professional contact details, first aid training, allergies, next of kin contact details.  These are needed for payroll and HMRC submission, employment and safeguarding purposes in connection with employment.Please note that we do not collect or store: credit/debit card details or ‘sensitive’ information, such as racial/ethnic origin, political beliefs, religious/similar beliefs, Trade Union membership; or sexual orientation/activities.Use of minor’s dataWe only collect or store any personal information about minors (students under the age of 18) in the context of processing their course enrolment, homestay accommodation, transport arrangements, visa applications and travel insurance. This is applicable where permission is obtained by us or a third party acting as the data controller directly from a parent or legal adult guardian to collect this information.We collect information on you when– You contact us for information by phone or via email– You work with us commercially as an agent, partner or contracted third party– You send us students’ personal details for course enrolments and accommodation arrangements– You accept to work for us as an employee– You provide your personal and home details to become a homestay provider– You use or interact with us via our website or our social media accountsUse of cookies:We may use cookies on our company websites for two reasons:Statistical purposes to track how many users we have and how often they visit our websites. We collect information about which pages are most frequently visited, from what type of users and from which countries.We may use other organisations to collect anonymous user information, sometimes through cookies and web beacons, so they are able to analyse how the website is being used and the number of visitors.You can turn cookies off but you may not be able to use all services on our websites then. This is because we will not be able to limit what you see by using cookies. However, you will still be able to see our editorial content.By using our websites, you are agreeing to the use of cookies as described here.What legal bases we use for processing your dataWe use different legal bases depending upon the purpose for collecting your data in the first instance:For all data collected to sign up for a product or service, such as our annual homestay newsletter, we process the data using Legitimate Interest, i.e. you are able to access an extensive range of information in exchange for supplying your information, and we have a relationship where the balance of benefits is in your favour. You always have a choice in the management of your data in this manner and can opt out of processing under this basis at any time.When you provide data in the course of the purchase of a service (like a course) or under explicit request, we process your data under Contract, i.e. your data is necessary for the fulfilment of the service and task required. Any additional contact, i.e. telling you about another service closely related to the service you have bought is managed under Legitimate Interest.Any secondary processing of your data, i.e. sharing with third parties, sending your messages on behalf of third parties, transfer to third countries, is managed under Consent. Under the terms of current data protection legislation, we will always make it as easy as possible for you to opt out of unwanted processing, providing it does not restrict our ability to provide you with the service you have requested.How long we keep data and how we dispose of itWe collect data for a wide range of purposes so we do not have a defined retention period, unless specified by law. For each individual service we define a carefully assessed time-frame within which we retain your data.After this, data is managed to ensure that it is either erased from our system, minimised and retained for legal reasons, or pseudo-anonymised and retained on a global suppression list to ensure that you do not receive unwanted messaging from us.Your RightsUnder current data protection legislation, you have the right to rectify, erase or restrict the processing of your data without undue delay. You may also request access to the data we hold on you.To do this or to update your personal information at any time, please contact the school on 01202 422300 or by email 1966@southbourneschool.co.ukDisclosing or sharing your dataYour personal data may be shared within the group of employees and contracted third party companies working for Southbourne School of English e.g. when there is a crossover between services and processes where your data is necessary.  We may make other organisations’ services available, when requested by you. We will process any information that we collect when you access or request a service provided by another organisation under this privacy policy. Information these other organisations collect is governed by their own privacy policies. We will not share your personal information with others for marketing purposes. Legal information on how to contact usUnder the current Applicable Laws we have to specify who the data controller is for Southbourne School of English, provided via our websites, events, email communications, etc.  The data controller is the organisation responsible for protecting information and, in the case of the personal information directly related to employees, homestay providers, individual students and contracted third parties (e.g. insurance, visas, transport), the controller is Southbourne School of English.For personal information relating to the enrolment of group of students and the processing of their data for other purposes, the agents are the responsible data controllers and Southbourne School of English  is the data processor.. If you would like access to or a copy of the personal information we hold about you, to request a correction, or if you have any questions about how we may use it, or to make a complaint, please contact please contact the school on 01202 422300 or by email 1966@southbourneschool.co.ukRequests will be dealt with and responded to within a reasonable period, not longer than 30 days.If you are not satisfied with the way our request was handled, you have the right to lodge a complaint with the supervisory authority:Information Commissioner’s Office (ICO): https://ico.org.uk/concerns/Telephone: +44(0)3031231113DisclaimerThe information contained in the website is for general information purposes only.  The information is provided by Southbourne School of English and while we endeavour to keep the information up to date and correct, we make no representations or warranties of any kind, express or implied, about the completeness, accuracy, reliability, suitability or availability with respect to the website or the information, products, services, or related graphics contained on the website for any purpose.  Any reliance you place on such information is therefore strictly at your own risk.In no event will we be liable for any loss or damage including without limitation, indirect or consequential loss or damage, or any loss or damage whatsoever arising from loss of data or profits arising out of, or in connection with, the use of this website.Through this website you are able to link to other websites which are not under the control of Southbourne School of English.  We have no control over the nature, content and availability of those sites.  The inclusion of any links does not necessarily imply a recommendation or endorse the views expressed within them.Every effort is made to keep the website up and running smoothly.  However, Southbourne School of English takes no responsibility for, and will not be liable for, the website being temporarily unavailable due to technical issues beyond our control.About Southbourne School of EnglishSouthbourne School of English is a family-run business founded in 1966. It occupies purpose-built premises situated in the middle of a typical English suburb in the seaside town of Bournemouth with only a ten-minute walk to the sea.
Quick LinksStarting at Southbourne School of EnglishAdult Language CoursesJunior Language CoursesHow to Book Your CourseTravelling to BritainSchool ActivitiesOur LocationAccommodation & WelfareContact Us
Southbourne School of English
30 Beaufort Road,
Southbourne, Bournemouth,
Dorset, BH6 5AL
+44 (0) 1202 422300
Email Us© 2018 Southbourne School of English | Privacy & Cookies | Terms | Quality English
Site by Crowd
